ANANT SHARMA

Contact

Address

Rohini, Delhi, 110089

Phone

9953575975

E-mail

anant.sharma592@gmail.co

WWW

https://zety.com/profile/anant-sharma/337

Skills

JavaScript,ReactJS,JQuery

Excellent

Redux, Node JS , Express.js, Angular 7

Very Good

Firebase, MySQL, Postgres

Very Good

JIRA,Git,SVN

Very Good

Operating Systems: Linux ,
Mac, Windows 10/XP

Very Good

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Good

JAVA,TypeScript

4+ years of extensive experience in developing **responsive**, **single page** and **serverless** web applications using technologies such as **ReactJS**, Angular7, **NodeJS**, **Firebase**, Java across several domains like **Chatbots**, **Healthcare**, **ERP**.

Exposure to SDLC with thorough knowledge of analysis, design, development and testing of web applications and client server applications in an **Agile** development environment with strong verbal and written communication skills.

Work History

2020-02 -Current

Software Engineer (MERN Stack)

Appy Pie LLP, Noida, UTTAR PRADESH

- Developing an all-in-one platform to build and launch conversational chatbots without coding.
- Implemented UI design using Bootstrap, HTML and CSS.
- Created custom, general use modules and components which extends the core ReactJS modules.
- Used Redux for state management and tools like
 Babel and Webpack for compiling and bundling of code.
- Created RESTful APIs and middlewares using NodeJS, ExpressJS.
- Third party integrations like Facebook, Zoom, Google drive and deploying chatbots on FB messenger and WhatsApp
- Used Firebase real-time database and functions for serverless backend.
- Implemented token-based authentication using **JWT** and **OAuth2.0** authorization.

2018-05 -2020-02

Senior Software Engineer

Samin Tekmindz India Pvt Ltd, Noida, UTTAR PRADESH

- Developed an OpenMRS based EMR(Electronic Medical Record) system for The International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC).
- Gathered specs from client to create a feasible workflow.
- Created custom,re-useable modules and

Average

Angular Material, Spring
Boot, Apache Of Biz

Average

components which extends the core **Angular7** modules.

- Solved problems using a combination of JavaScript,
 JSON, and JQuery.
- Followed Agile development and consistently delivered new features on time during sprints.
- Presented solutions to the client when they want out of scope issues to be solved.
- Communicated updates in daily scrum meetings using JIRA software.
- Responsible for assuring code quality (adherence to coding best practices, design and coding standards) through detailed code reviews.

2016-10 -2018-04

Software Engineer

Samin Tekmindz India Pvt Ltd, Noida, UTTAR PRADESH

- An ERP system developed for United Nations(
 Afghanistan), using Apache OfBiz F/w and Java.
- Utilized MVC principals to ensure a clean architecture and a lean code base for maximum.
- Involved in creating database schema and implemented UI design using Bootstrap, HTML and CSS.
- Used Javascript libraries like Jquery to make application dynamic.

Education

2015-06

2010-03

2016-02 -	Post Graduate Diploma in Mobile
2016-08	Computing (PGDMC): Mobile Computing

CDAC - Noida GPA:75%

2011-08 - B.Tech: Electronics and Communications

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University - Rohini Delhi

GPA: 65%

2007-03 - High School: Science Education

The Air Force School - Delhi

12th: 72% 10th: 86%